Guide to the Primary Writing records, 1973-2019 MS2393
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Primary Writing small press records and Phyllis Rosenzweig personal correspondence collection
1973-2019
1994-2009
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Rosenzweig, Phyllis D.
Downs, Buck
Darragh, Tina
Inman, P. (Peter Inman)
Joselow, Beth
Lally, Michael, 1942-
Ward, Diane, 1956-
Lang, Doug
Winch, Terence
Retallack, Joan, October 13, 1941
Mandel, Tom, 1942-
MS2393
5.5 Linear Feet 10 document boxes
This collection contains publications (journal issues, postcards, monographs) related to the Primary Writing publication as well as small presses in Washington D.C., manuscript drafts, correspondence both related to the journal publication and other Primary Writing related work between Phyllis Rosenzweig, Diane Ward, and contributing authors, and a small amount of organization records related to the production of a journal including layout mock-ups, and receipts. There is also a series with correspondence between Phyllis Rosenzweig and writers that cover topics beyond Primary Writing. These records date from 1973-2019 with the bulk of the records dating between 1994-2009. Primary Writing was a small press publication devoted to work by contemporary poets in the D.C. area, New York, the West Coast and beyond. Co-edited by Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig, it consists of 44 issues published between April 1995 and February 2008. The issues varied in format from postcard, to broadside, to stapled booklet, depending on the content of each one, and were mailed to an extended audience of writers and special collection libraries.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: Publications and correspondence, Phyllis Rosenzweig personal correspondence with writers, DC small press publications, and Doug Lang correspondence and publications
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Phyllis Rosenzweig, 2020 October 30 (Accession 2020.028).
Separated Materials
With this donation came issues of the journal Washington Review. After weeding out duplicates the remaining issues were added to the serial holdings in Special Collections. The issues included from this accession are v. 9 no. 1 - no. 4, v. 10 no. 2 - no. 3, v. 13 no. 2. The call no. for this publication is NX 510.W3 W32.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains publications (journal issues, postcards, monographs) related to the Primary Writing publication as well as small presses in Washington D.C., manuscript drafts, correspondence both related to the journal publication and other Primary Writing related work between Phyllis Rosenzweig, Diane Ward, and contributing authors, and a small amount of organization records related to the production of a journal including layout mock-ups, and receipts. There is also a series with correspondence between Phyllis Rosenzweig and writers that cover topics beyond Primary Writing. These records date from 1973-2019 with the bulk of the records dating between 1994-2009.
Biographical note
Phyllis Rosenzweig is curator emerita of the Hirshhorn Museum & Sculpture Garden. She has also taught adjunct classes at GWU and the Corcoran College of Art + Design, and organized several exhibitions of contemporary art in D.C. and the Bronx, New York. She affiliates herself with a group of D.C. poets (including Tina Darragh, Lynne Dreyer, Peter Inman, Diane Ward, Bernard Welt, and Terence Winch), and a community originally formed around Folio Bookstore and readings organized there by poet Doug Lang in the 1970s. She currently edits Primary Writing Books, devoted to publishing work by D.C. area writers.
Biographical note
Poet Diane Ward (November 9, 1956- ) was born in Washington, DC and attended the Corcoran School of Art. She was initially associated with the first wave of Language poetry in the 1970s. She has published more than a dozen works of poetry and been included in numerous anthologies.
Historical note
Primary Writing was a small press publication devoted to work by contemporary poets in the D.C. area, New York, the West Coast and beyond. Co-edited by Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig, it consists of 44 issues published between April 1995 and February 2008. The issues varied in format from postcard, to broadside, to stapled booklet, depending on the content of each one, and were mailed to an extended audience of writers and special collection libraries. Three issues of an earlier version of Primary Writing were published by Phyllis Rosenzweig in 1983, 1984, and 1988.
Experimental poetry -- 20th century.; Poetry -- 20th century; Creative writing; Washington (D.C.)
- Publications and correspondence, 1983-2019; MS2393 Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence, published issues of Primry Writing, monographs, and manuscripts. Primary Writing ceased publication as a periodical in 2007. In 2011 Phyllis Rosenzweig began publishing Primary Writing Books, books and chapbooks of writing by D.C. area authors. Six, of a projected 10, have been printed so far. This correspondence is specifically related to Primary Writing.
  Arrangement
  Arrangement maintained the original order created by the donor.
  - Run of Primary Writing, 1995-2008; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Note provided by the donor: One copy of each issue of Primary Writing, the small press magazine published by Phyllis Rosenzweig and Diane Ward (then living in Los Angeles). Formats vary from postcard to several pages. Includes complete index; also copy attached separately.
  - Primary Writing: Ledger, 1995-2008; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Note provided by the donor: Miscellaneous receipts for printing, etc.; paper samples, etc.
  - Primary Writing: Subscriptions, 1995-2008; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Note provided by the donor: Miscellaneous correspondence with subscribers
  - Primary Writing Mailing List, 1995-2008; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Note provided by the donor: Many versions of mailing list (issues mailed out for free) and notes for revisions as names are added, deleted, addresses change or issues are returned without forwarding addresses
  - Title: Morning; Issue: #1; Author(s): Laura Moriarty, 1995 January - March; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4a)
    Format: Postcards
  - Untitled; Issue: #2; Author(s): Rod Smith and Martina Hügli, 1995 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Format: Poster
  - Untitled; Issue: #3/4; Author(s): Norma Cole, Noah de Lissovoy, Hannah Weiner, Tina Darragh, 1995 October; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Format: Broadside
  - Title: The Main Idea; Issue: #5; Author(s): Beverly Dahlen, 1996 January; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Format: Postcard
  - Untitled; Issue: #6; Author(s): Peter Seaton, Jessica Grim, 1996 April; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Untitled; Issue: #7; Author(s): Joan Retallack, 1996 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Title: for Siobhan's Drawings; Issue: #8; Author(s): Fiona Templeton, 1996 October; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Format: 8 pp. Booklet
  - Title: A Call from Dr. Julie; Issue: #9; Author(s): Jack Collom, 1997 January; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Title: Chapeau 3 Sestinas; Issue: #10; Author(s): Sheila Murphy, 1997 April; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Title: Blood Sightings, Greed, 610, 611, 613, Rambling, Soft, Buck, Purl 2; Issue: #11; Author(s): Judith Goldman, Simon Perchik, Andrew Levy, 1997 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Title: fr. Turntable, Wannabe, Propping faces; Issue: #12; Author(s): Melanie Neilsen, Suzi Roberts, 1997 December; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Format: 6 pp. stapled
  - Title: rembrandt; Issue: #13; Author(s): W.B. Keckler, 1998 January; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Title: Da Kine, Braque & Wife; Issue: #14; Author(s): Juliana Spahr, P. Inman, 1998 April; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Title: Shewn; Issue: #15; Author(s): Tom Raworth, 1998 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Title: Post Industrials; Issue: #16; Author(s): Abigail Child, Buck Downs, 1998 October; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Format: 4 pp. envelope
  - Title: Rod Moth; Issue: #17; Author(s): Lee Ann Brown, 1999 January; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Title: Apostle Decision; Issue: #18; Author(s): Heather Fuller, 1999 April; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Title: Keeper; Issue: #19; Author(s): Lynne Dreyer, 1999 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Format: 4 pp. stapled
  - Unititled; Issue: #20; Author(s): Jocelyn Saidenberg, 1999 October; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Title: [Xmas colab]; Issue: #21; Author(s): Jack Collom &, 1999 December; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Title: 2000 postcards; Issue: #22; Author(s): Bruce Andrews, Rae Armantrout, Dody Bellamy, Tina Darragh, Elaine Equi, Steve Farmer, Susan Gevirtz, Hung Q. Tu, Lisa Jarnot ("Old"), Doug Lang, Aaron D. Levy, Karen Mac Cormack, Jackson MacLow, Yedda Morrison, Sheila E. Murphy, Kit Robinson, Phyllis Rosenzweig, Eleni Sikelianos, Rod Smith, Alexandra & Rod Smith, Anne Tardos, Fiona Templeton, Elizabeth Treadwell, Diane Ward, 2000 Postcards (series of 24 postcards); MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Format: Series of 24 postcards
  - Title: From Some Haitian Proverbs; Issue: #23; Author(s): Rod Smith, 2001 April; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Title: repeats 'just space'; Issue: #24; Author(s): Leslie Scalapino, 2001 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Title: w/ires for.. .; Issue: #25; Author(s): Tina Darragh, 2001 September; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Title: from Example; Issue: #26; Author(s): E. Tracy Grinell, 2002 January; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Title: Rare Earth; Issue: #27; Author(s): Kim Rosenfeld, 2002 April; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Title: Alma's Forehead; Issue: #28; Author(s): Alice Notley, 2002 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Title: Jacob's Ladder; Issue: #29; Author(s): Charles Bernstein, 2002 December; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Untitled; Issue: #30; Author(s): Alison Cobb, Therese Bachand, 2003 February; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Format: Broadside, 6 pp.
  - Unititled; Issue: #31; Author(s): Heather Fuller, 2003 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Untitled; Issue: #31 [sic]; Author(s): Carole Mirakove, Will Alexander, 2003 October; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Title: Going Back to the Real Mother...; Issue: #32; Author(s): Lorraine Graham, 2004 April; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Untitled; Issue: #33; Author(s): Steve Benson, 2004 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Unititled; Issue: #34; Author(s): Norma Cole, 2004 October; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Donor notes that this folder is empty. Format: 4 pp. stapled
  - Title: from Dear Land; Issue: #35; Author(s): E Tracy Grinnell, 2005 January; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Format: 8 pp. stapled
  - Untitled; Issue: #36; Author(s): Kaia Sand, 2005 May; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Untitled; Issue: #37; Author(s): Brenda Iijima, 2005 October; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Untitled; Issue: #38; Author(s): Kristen Gallagher, 2006 January; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Title: Aquarium 2 poems; Issue: #39; Author(s): Jane Sprague, Jen Hofer, 2006 May; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Title: Das Greenspan; Issue: #40; Author(s): Jules Boykoff, 2006 July; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Format: 3 pp. envelope
  - Untitled; Issue: #41; Author(s): Stephanie Rioux, 2006 October; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Donor notes that this folder is empty. Format: 8 pp. stapled
  - Title: Brakhage Notes, Dear compagno, Mein Freund; Issue: #42; Author(s): Tom Orange, Joseph Mosconi, 2007 February; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Donor notes that this folder is empty. Format: 10 pp. stapled
  - Title: e.d.; w.w. Ladybug; Issue: #43; Author(s): Cathy Eisenhower, Laura Moriarty, 2007 May; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Donor notes that this folder is empty. Format: 6 pp. stapled
  - Primary Writing #44, 2007; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Donor notes that this folder is empty
  - Title:; Issue: #41 [sic] Final issue; Author(s): P. Inman, Mel Nichols, Jessica Grim, Marcella Durand, Miles Champion, 2008 February; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Format: 21 pp. stapled
  - Primary Writing #s 1, 2, 3, 1983-1988; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Note provided by the donor: The original, earlier, iteration of Primary Writing published only by Phyllis Rosenzweig, conceived as single issues each devoted to one long work by an individual writer. Only three issues were published: #1"Via Negativa" by Jane DeLynn, 1983, 22 pp.stapled, #2 "3 Novels" by Doug Lang, 1988, 18 pp. stapled.* #2 "3 Novels" by Doug Lang, 1988, 18 pp. stapled.*
    *Originally projected to be #2 but was delayed so was preceded by #3.
  - Via Negativa by Jane DeLynn, Undated; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Note provided by the donor: Original typed copy, drafts, design and printing documents
  - Scale Sliding [Ambiguous Figures] by Tina Darragh, Undated; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Three Novels by Doug Lang, Undated; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Note provided by the donor: Original typed copies, corrected drafts, etc.
  - Correspondence re: Primary Writing #s 1, 2, 3, 1983-1985; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Note provided by the donor: Mailing list, subscriptions and miscellaneous correspondence with: Lyn Hejinian, Kevin Killiam, Richard Kostelanetz, Gerard Melanga, Peter Seaton, James Sherry, and others.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 1994-1995, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets Guy Bennett, Norma Cole, Jack Collom, Beverly Dahlen, Tina Darragh, Connie Deanovich, Barbara Guest, Lyn Hejinian, Lisa Jarnot, Andrew Levy, Kevin Killian, Laura Moriarty, Jennifer Moxley, Charles North, Peter Seaton, Rod Smith, Hannah Weiner, and Diane Ward. Note: throughout, fax correspondence from Diane Ward to Phyllis Rosenzweig is often on "Chris Hauty" letterhead. Chris Hauty was Diane Ward's husband at the time; their children are George and Jackson.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 1996, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets Bruce Andrews, Jack Collom, Daniel Davidson, Kevin Killian,Noah de Lissovoy, Jessica Grim, Andrew Levy, Melanie Neilson, Jena Osman, Suzi Roberts, Peter Seaton, Fiona Templeton.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 1997, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Guy Bennett, Abigail Child, Jack Collom, Noah deLissovoy, Johanna Drucker, Michael Gottlieb, Sheila Murphy, Jena Osman,Tom Raworth, and Juliana Spahr,
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 1998, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Steve Benson, Lee Ann Brown, Abigail Child, Jack Collom, Jacques Debrot, Buck Downs, Lynne Dreyer, Steve Farmer, Heather Fuller, Peter Inman, W.B. Keckler, Kevin Killian, Karen Mac Cormack, Douglas Messerli, Sheila Murphy, Melanie Neilsen, Charles North, Simon Perchik, Kit Robinson, Juliana Spahr, and others.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 1999 [1/2], MS2393 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Rae Armentrout, Dodie Bellamy, Alan Bernheimer, Mei mei Bersenbrugge, Abigail Child, Jack Collom, Connie Deanovich, Lynne Dreyer, Elaine Equi, Steve Farmer, Heather Fuller, Susan Gevirtz, Hung Q. Tu, Lisa Jarnot, Karen Mac Cormack, Jackson Mac Low, Yedda Morrison, Sheila Murphy, Martin Nakell, James Nordland, Lee Riley-Hammer, Kit Robinson, Martha Ronk, Jocelyn Saidenberg, Eleni Sikelianos, Rod Smith, Pete Spence, Anne Tardos, Elizabeth Treadwell, John-Paul Walty, and others; correspondence with Ann Vickery, and George Hauty (Diane's son).
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 1999 [2/2], MS2393 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2000, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig (including text of an interview between Diane Ward and Kevin Davies for "Philly Talks"); correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Bruce Andrews, Jack Collom, Tina Darragh, Jane DeLynn, Heather Fuller, Susan Gevirtz, E. Tracy Grinnell, Richard Kostelanetz, Doug Lang, Aaron Levy, Karen MacCormack, Tom Orange, Leslie Scalapino, Peter Seaton, Anne Tardos, and George Hauty and Chris Hauty and several returned postcards.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2001, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Therese Bachand, Allison Cobb, Jack Collom,Tina Darragh, E.Tracy Grinnell, Beth Joselow, Richard Kostelanetz, Bernadette Mayer, Alice Notley, Leslie Scalapino, Jessica Smith, Rod Smith.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2002, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Steve Benson, Charles Bernstein, Allison Cobb, Rob Fitterman, Sheila Murphy, Alice Notley, Kim Rosenfeld, Jessica Smith, Rod Smith.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2003, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Will Alexander, Abigail Child, Norma Cole, Heather Fuller, Lorraine Graham, Michael McMillen, Carol Mirakove, Sheila Murphy, Michael Sappol, Juliana Spahr.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2004, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Steve Benson, Jules Boykoff, Jessica Grim, E. Tracy Grinnell, Kevin Killian, Michael Lally, Sheila Murphy, Tom Orange, Kaia Sand,
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2005, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Jules Boykoff, Kristen Gallagher, Brenda Iijihma, Walter Lew, Karen Mac Cormack, Jena Osman, Simon Perchik, Kaia Sand, Jane Sprague, Elizabeth Treadwell, Nathan Whiting.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2006, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Abigail Child, Jack Collom, Cathy Eisenhower, Peter Gannick, Kevin Killian, Brenda Iijima, Sheila Murphy, Mel Nichols, Tom Orange, Stephanie Rioux, Jane Sprague.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2007, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Miles Champion, Tina Darragh, Marcella Durand, Cathy Eisenhower, Jessica Grim, Brenda Iijima, Peter Inman, Richard Kostelanitz, Laura Moriarty, Sheila Murphy, Mel Nichols.
  - Primary Writing Correspondence 2008-2009 +, MS2393 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence between Diane Ward and Phyllis Rosenzweig; correspondence with and/or typescripts from poets: Jules Boykoff, Miles Champion, Marcella Durand, Jessica Grim, Sheila Murphy, Andrew Schelling, Juliana Spahr. Also: Undated postcard from Judith Goldman; copy of [undated?] postcard from Lee Ann Brown; new year's postcards from Sheila Murphy, 1910 and 1918; one unidentified and undated poem on the inside of an envelope addressed to Phyllis Rosenzweig.
  - Primary Writing Books, 2012-2019; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Note provided by the donor: Primary Writing ceased publication as a periodical in 2007. In 2011 Phyllis Rosenzweig began publishing Primary Writing Books, books and chapbooks of writing by D.C. area authors. Six, of a projected 10, have been printed so far. One copy of each are included here. They are: Phyllis Rosenzweig. Girls (2012), Doug Lang. dérangé (2012)* *This book is out of print and very rare. Very few copies exist, Ken Jacobs. Unmet (2012), Lynne Dreyer. The Under Arc (2015), Cathy Eisenhower. animalitos (2017), Chris Mason. Some of the Methods of Performing Poetry Employed in and Around Baltimore from the Late 60's to the Early Teens by Poets in Their Late Teens to Early 60's (2019)
  - Girls by Phyllis Rosenzweig, Undated; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Note provided by the donor: Mock-ups/dummies for printing and original snapshot; correspondence with Susan Campbell, poets Erica Kaufman and Doug Lang, Pat Kolmar, Clive Phillpot, and Katha Pollitt.
  - unmet by Ken Jacobs, 2015-2015; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Note provided by the donor: Correspondence with Ken Jacobs and Bob Allen (the designer)
  - The Under Arc by Lynne Dreyer, 2015-2015; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Note provided by the donor: Mock-ups, invoice from printer, correspondence with Bob Allen, misc. rough ideas for cover.
  - animalitos by Cathy Eisenhower, Undated; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Note provided by the donor: Invoice from printer, several drafts, correspondence with Cathy Eisenhower and Bob Allen.
  - Some of the Methods of Performing Poetry... by Chris Mason, Undated; MS2393 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Note provided by the donor: Invoice from printer, several drafts and mock-ups, correspondence with Chris Mason and Bob Allen.
- Phyllis Rosenzweig personal correspondence with writers, 1982-2012; MS2393 Series 2
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains correspondence between Phyllis Rosenzweig and numerous D.C. writers. In many instances a folder also contains original manuscripts. This personal correspondence does include some of the same people as in Series 1 and related to Primary Writing, but in this series the correspondence is more general and far ranging.
  - Barry Alpert, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Donald Britton (about), Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Tina Darragh [1/2], Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Tina Darragh [2/2], Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Jane De Lynn, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lynne Dreyer [1/2], 1982-2007; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Lynne Dreyer [2/2], 1982-2007; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lynne Dreyer [1/2], Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lynne Dreyer [2/2], Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Jessica Grim, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Peter Inman, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Beth Joselow, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kevin Killian and Dodie Bellamy, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Tom Mandel, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Magus Magnus, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Melanie Neilson, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Tom Orange Orono Conference, 2008; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Tom Raworth, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 11)